# 为什么剌这个 便于入味
Why would you cut it? To help flavour penetration
# 今儿咱们做一个改良菜 很简单
Today we are going to make a modified and improved dish, very simple
# 我们用沙姜提肉方的味 这个不一样
We are using sand ginger to season the meat. This is quite unique.
# 鲜沙姜的味道 你可以说说吧
The smell of fresh sand ginger, you can describe it.
# 它这个香有一股药香
There is herbal scent in it
# 跟咱们那鲜姜不太一样
It’s different from ordinary fresh ginger
# 它有种特殊的香味
The scent is quite special
# 现在我们把水坐开了
We have boiled the water
# 我喜欢 这边焯着水 咱那边切料吧
I like it (sand ginger). Let's parboil the meat while cutting the other ingredients on the side
# 搁点葱焯一下 黄酒
Add some spring onion and huangjiu rice wine
# 扎一下 好入味 让它的血水呲出来
Poke some holes in it to penetrate the flavour and help release the blood
# 该切小料了吧
Now let’s cut the other ingredients
# 你看这个料很简单 这可以带皮走
The preparation is rather simple. We can cook them with the skin on
# 一拍就行 拍了入味
Just crush it and that is enough for the flavour penetration
# 这点就差不多够了
This amount is alright
# 这点香料很简单
The spices combination is quite simple
# 就三种 桂皮 大料 香叶 就三种就够了
Cinnamon, star anise and bay leaves. These three spices are enough
# 然后我们把料稍微洗一下
Rinse the spices
# 它真的脏
They are quite dirty
# 倒油 把葱姜蒜搁进去就行了
Add some oil, put in the onion, ginger and garlic
# 香味出来了吧 干葱拍一下师父
It’s quite aromatic. Crush the shallots, master
# 小干葱跟洋葱似的 但是不是洋葱
Shallots are quite similar to onions, but they are not the same
# 增加香味
To enhance the aroma
# 从这气味的变化 香气出来了
You can smell the change. The aroma has been released
# 它主要出在鲜沙姜的味
The main aroma is the aroma of sand ginger
# 先加黄酒 突出酒香
Add huangjiu rice wine first to accentuate the fragrance of the wine
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 搁了几粒冰糖
Add some white rock sugar
# 然后啤酒 改小火
Next is to add the beer, then turn the heat down
# 这个菜是不加水的
We don’t have to add water while cooking this dish
# 一罐不够 再来一罐
One can is not enough, one more
# 这回就差不多了
That's it.
# 香味就够了
The fragrance would be enough
# 魏哥这肉用翻一下么 翻一下肉
Brother Wei, do we need to flip the meat? -Yes, flip it now.
# 没毛病 方方正正
Great, fairly square-shaped
# 汤调好了味了 你看味道非常香
The soup is well seasoned, the flavour is awesome
# 小亮你这回再尝一下
Xiao Liang, try this again
# 我这都闻着味儿了
I can smell the aroma
# 把这汤搁到高压锅 准备煎肉了
Pour the soup into pressure cooker and prepare to pan fry the meat
# 把这水得沾一下
Wipe off the excess water on the meat
# 扎一下 就跟您教我们做扣肉似的
Poke some holes, that’s similar to make Kou Rou (stewed pork belly) as you taught us
# 来点蜂蜜
# 上色，上颜色，而且有蜂蜜的香味
Add some honey, to darken the colour and add some fragrance
# 先煎皮
Fry the pork skin first
# 得上盖
Cover the lid
# 一定要晃悠晃悠网友们 省的糊了
Remember to shake it around, or else the meat might burn
# 关火
Turn off the heat
# 一定要注意安全 放到水里头
We must be careful. Now put the meat into water
# 这个煎完肉你看 用钢丝球
Look at the pan-fried meat. Use steel wool to clean the surface.
# 该剞刀了
Time to score the pork surface.
# 不切段剌一半 你看见没有 这刀口
Cut half way through, just like this.
# 三刀
Three cuts each direction.
# 为什么剌这个 便于入味
Why should we cut the surface? To help the infusion of flavor.
# 齐活 进锅了啊
Done and put into the pressure cooker.
# 二十五分钟
Stew for 25 minutes.
# 慢点 这家伙香啊
Slowly. It smells so good.
# 你看煎过的肉就不一样吧
You see, fried meat is just better.
# 看拿筷子扎扎 特别熟了
Poke it with chopsticks. It’s well cooked.
# 砂锅 油
Add oil to the clay pot.
# 沙姜 干葱 蒜子搁进去得了
Put sand ginger, shallot and garlic in.
# 肉取出来了 你看这个肉
Take out the meat. Check this out.
# 跟那红烧肉还是不一样 全是煎的
This is quite different from Red Braised Pork. This meat was thoroughly fried.
# 鲜沙姜的味非常浓
Very strong fragrance from the fresh sand ginger.
# 一点水没有 全是啤酒
No water added, only beer.
# 这料还要么 不要了
Keep these spices? -Nah, throw them away.
# 我们再来点葱 小香葱
Add some green onions.
# 这香气就出来了吧
The fragrance comes out already.
# 这就行了
That’s it.
# 这肉是这样 拿篦子
Ok now the meat is in, you use a sieve to (filter the soup into the clay pot)
# 这样再把香味儿焖进去 行了这就
and braise the meat to infuse the flavour.
# 应该再焖个十分钟就够了
Braise it for another 10 minutes would be enough.
# 这个汤汁焖没了就行
Reduce the liquid and we are all set.
# 这个菜挺有意思吧
This is quite an interesting dish.
# 差不多了可以出锅了
That’s about it, ready to serve.
# 带点汁 小亮给你
With some sauce. Here you are, Xiao Liang.
# 小魏给你一个
One for you, Xiao Wei.
# 那我就不客气了
I will start tasting first.
# 肉还得必须得吃肥的
The fatty part is the best.
# 这跟咱们用糖色烧完真是完全不一样
It’s a completely different method compared to colouring with caramelized sugar.
# 这里面全是蒜和沙姜的香
The garlic and sand ginger aroma are swelling.
# 尤其这肉香 香的你能顶脑门
You can sense the deliciousness by the fragrance of the meat.
# 绝对让你吃出肉的醇香来
The mellowness of the pork is perfectly brought out.
# 确实是肥而不腻
Indeed! Fatty texture but no greasy taste.
# 而且干葱跟蒜子香味
Also you can tell that the flavours of shallots,
# 还有沙姜的香味 融到一块了
garlics and sand ginger had infused together.
# 这样烧肉的醇香和散着烧不一样
Braising Pork in a whole piece achieves a different flavour profile compared to diced pieces.
# 肉就得大块 整
The key is to use one big piece of meat.
# 你看这两天
Recently,
# 我们的粉丝网友提了这个问题
Our fans asked us:
# 说现在韭菜花正是上市的季节
Now chives flower is in season.
# 来个小视频
They want us to make a video
# 怎么腌韭菜花
On how to make pickled chives flower.
# 一把韭菜花买来以后
After getting a bunch of chives flower...
# 把花瓣的根的地方有一些
There are some yellowish petals
# 小黄的那些花瓣
around the flower roots.
# 把它要去掉
Get rid of these.
# 然后洗干净
And wash them throughly.
# 在通风的地方
Put them at a ventilated place
# 要控干水
Drain all the water.
# 然后用我们粉碎机
Then we will use a food processor
# 把它破碎
to grind the chives flowers
# 破碎的时候
While grinding,
# 因为粉碎机里要有水
we need to add water to the food processor.
# 所以我们要晾点凉白开
So we need to prepare some pre-boiled, room-temperature water.
# 开水
# 必须是凉白开
Boiled Water.
Must be cooled boiled water.
# 用矿泉不行
Don’t use bottled water.
# 为什么
Why?
# 这个就是矿泉水不行
It just doesn’t work by experience.
# 非得是凉白开
Cooled boiled water is the only valid option.
# 凉白开是开水
Cooled boiled water has been boiled
# 对
Right
# 矿泉水不是开水
Mineral water or bottled water haven’t been boiled.
# 用开水的好处是什么
What is the advantages of boiled water?
# 开水它不容易坏啊
Pickles are less likely to rot with boiled water.
# 它水是开的
It has been boiled.
# 因为经过高温消毒了
It’s sanitized at high temperature.
# 杀菌了
Heat-sanitized!
# 然后在打碎当中
Then when you grind it,
# 倒到盆里头
Pour the content into a pot.
# 加大盐
Add coarse salt.
# 加大盐加到什么比例
How much coarse salt?
# 以咸菜为准
Take the recipe of pickled cabbage for reference.
# 10:1
It’s about a 10:1 ratio.
# 十斤菜搁一斤盐
1 kg of salt for every 10 kg of vegetables.
# 10:1
Ten to one.
# 有的说我不喜欢吃那么咸
If you would like it less salty.
# 也得十斤菜
Then for ten jin (5 kg) of vegetables,
# 搁八两盐
you need eight liang (400 g) of salt
# 就400克的盐
That’s about 400 grams of salt.
# 这样腌出这菜呢
After that,
# 我们还要加一点花椒
We also need to add a grain of Sichuan peppercorn.
# 倒一点白酒啊
Pour in a bit of Baijiu (strong Chinese liquor).
# 然后在这盆里头
Then you want to cover the pot
# 拿盖
with a lid,
# 或者拿保鲜膜绷上
or you can use plastic wrap.
# 要让他发酵
Let it ferment
# 发酵过程中放那不管了
You don’t have to do much while the fermentation process is going on.
# 第二天呢
The second day.
# 还要拿干净的勺子或者筷子
You need to stir it up
# 要把它搅拌一下
With clean spoons or chopsticks.
# 但是不能放在铝盆里头
Make sure that you are not using a aluminum container.
# 一定要放一个瓷盆
Use a porcelain pot.
# 搪瓷盆
Enamel pot.
# 或者我们那种陶瓷盆
Or the traditional ceramic pot.
# 搅完拌以后再给它封上
Cover it again after stirring.
# 放了一个阴凉地发酵十五天
Store the container in a cool, dry place for 15 days.
# 这不是一次就能成的
It is not enough to stir it only once.
# 对前边要有四五次的搅拌
Yeah, you need to stir the content four or five times during the early fermentation stage.
# 等到15天以后
After 15 days.
# 把它拌好了
Stir it up throughly.
# 我们选几个干净的瓶子
Pick up several clean bottles.
# 拿开水烫一下
Sanitize with hot water.
# 或蒸一下消毒
Or steam them before use.
# 然后把韭菜花灌进去
Then we can pour in the pickled chives flowers.
# 拧紧了盖
Cap it tightly
# 然后放到冰箱里头
with cap on tight.
# 你吃就不会坏了
It won’t go bad this way.
# 咸菜呢也会出现这个问题
The making of pickled cabbage shares the same problem.
# 比如这咸菜我们如果说
For instance, in the case of pickled cabbages,
# 不给他搅拌
If we don’t stir it up,
# 那咸菜汤上面会漂一层白膜
There will be a thin white film on the surface of the liquid.
# 但是它不是汤坏了了
It’s not because fungi grow in the soup.
# 就因为你在腌的时候
Instead, the white film shows that
# 它咸味和不咸的地方
during the fermentation process
# 它不均匀
the salt is not distributed evenly in the solution.
# 那起了白膜怎么办
What if we already have the white film?
# 那这缸子菜不能够扔了啊
Just don’t throw the pot out of your window,
# 很贵的也是
Picked stuff ain’t no cheap.
# 我们可以适当加点酒
We can add a little bit of liquor.
# 加一点红糖
Add in some brown sugar.
# 这白膜给它搅拌均匀以后
Stir up until the layer of white film is evenly mixed into the liquid.
# 这白膜第二天就下去了
The film should disappear the second day.
# 是吧
Yes!
# 还有一种办法呢
There’s another way around this.
# 实在不行
Last resort:
# 我们就把咸菜全部都捞出来
We can fish out all the pickled veges
# 把这咸菜汤给熬一下
and proceed to boil the liquid content
# 这个腌咸菜的水被污染了
The liquid is contaminated.
# 所以我们在拿咸菜的时候
So make sure that you wash your hands
# 手一定要干净
before handling the pickled veges.
# 不能蘸生水
Don’t get tap water on your hands.
# 最好有单独的筷子和勺子
It would be better to just use a separate set of chopsticks and spoons.
# 是吧
Right.
# 来取这咸菜
When taking out those pickled veges,
# 一旦腌咸菜的缸里边
If tap water manages to somehow
# 进了生水了
slide into the pot
# 洗菜没有控干的这些菜
Or you did not drain the veges after washing them
# 腌咸菜这汤 泡菜这汤
The liquid content in the pot
# 就特别容易坏
is likely to go bad.
# 关于韭菜花这块还有什么补充的吗
What else would you add for pickled Leek flowers?
# 没有
Nope
# 就是说你拿韭菜花
What you really should do is to take the making of pickled leek flowers
# 当做腌菜的一个案例
as a template for any pickled veges.
# 你比如我腌点黄瓜
For example, let’s say we are making pickled cucumbers,
# 腌点萝卜
pickled radish...
# 你看腌萝卜的时候
When processing radish,
# 洗干净以后
After washing it.
# 刮完皮或者不刮皮
Peeling the skin off or not.
# 我们把萝卜切成条
We cut radish into strips,
# 先用盐杀水
Sanitize the water with salt.
# 因为萝卜是先洗了
Because we wash the radish in the first step,
# 洗完以后
After washing it,
# 萝卜含的水气太大
The radish is probably soaked with water.
# 所以我们要先杀水
That’s the reason behind sanitizing the water with salt.
# 包括黄瓜
Also, in the case of cucumbers,
# 凡是含水量大的这些蔬菜
For veges with high water content,
# 都要用盐
We always want to use salt.
# 提前用盐把它杀水
use salt to cure it and remove excess water.
# 杀完水以后
After curing it,
# 我们控干了这水
We drain the water,
# 然后再入缸里头
then put the vegetables into the pot.
# 这样的萝卜腌出来
Only following these specific steps will the radish...
# 才会脆
have the desired crunchy texture to it.
# 明白
Got it!